<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Not A Journal by Gio</title>
    <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Not A Journal by Gio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 10:24:42 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/notes-from-peak/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 10:24:42 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/notes-from-peak/</guid>
      <description>These are my rather unorganized notes from &amp;ldquo;Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise&amp;rdquo; by Anders Ericsson and Robert Pool.
Take everything with a pinch of salt. They are what I found useful and worth highlighting from the book. Their density depends in part by the state of mind in which I was when reading or listening. Some times I write a lot of notes, other times less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Ego Is The Enemy</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2017-03-15-ego-is-the-enemy-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 06:13:24 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2017-03-15-ego-is-the-enemy-notes/</guid>
      <description>This are my rather not organized notes from Ego Is The Enemy by Ryan Holiday.
Books &amp;ldquo;about philosophy&amp;rdquo;, with a cover image pointing at ancient Greece and Rome, are not what I usually read. But I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I read this. Partially inspired by the will of going out of my filter bubble (as learnt from &amp;ldquo;The Inevitable&amp;rdquo;), event though this book is not completely out of it, as it has been recommended by the engine in Audible, marked as one of the best books of 2016, and read by some friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-09-08-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 09:23:12 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-09-08-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>The podcast Developer Tea recently released a two part series on deliberate practice (part 1 and part 2).
I first read about deliberate practice in &amp;ldquo;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You&amp;rdquo; by Cal Newport.
The concept is very attractive, and it has been proven very effective for athletes and musicians. But how can I build a deliberate practice strategy for my software development skills?
Does it even make sense?
It probably does, but only for a subset of things I guess.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Freelancers&#39; Show on Automation</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-30-what-to-automate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 09:54:41 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-30-what-to-automate/</guid>
      <description>Episode 216 of &amp;ldquo;The Freelancers&amp;rsquo; Show&amp;rdquo; has a great and original conversation on automation.
Unlike many other posts and podcasts on the topic, this one focus on how to find out what to automate, and why you should -or shouldn&amp;rsquo;t- automate something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measure Twice, Cut Once</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-28-measure-twice-cut-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 17:58:17 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-28-measure-twice-cut-once/</guid>
      <description>In an otherwise usual conversation about Agile-slash-Scrum which tells the same old story, Matt -the host- mentioned the carpentry rule:
 Measure Twice, Cut Once
 I think that&amp;rsquo;s a quite cool rule, and I shall keep it close to my heart.
I am a software developer to the core. My ideal work day is composed of only coding, no meeting, no emails, only code.
I am aware though that &amp;ldquo;just coding&amp;rdquo; or start coding without a plan can be, and most likely will be, counter productive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Remotely Interview with Laura Elizabeth</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-25-remote-work-laura-elizabeth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 07:22:59 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-25-remote-work-laura-elizabeth/</guid>
      <description>In episode 76 of the freelance transformation podcast Matt interviews Laura, a freelance solo designer that works entirely remotely.
There are a lot of good tips spread across the interview, but here&amp;rsquo;s my favourites:
 Send new clients a Starbucks/Costa/Café gift card. Try to guest post in blogs where your target market hangs out. Note that these are probably different from the ones where you hang out. Use copy that connects in your website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maxwell&#39;s Equations</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-24-17-equations-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 08:06:10 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-24-17-equations-11/</guid>
      <description>Maxwell&amp;rsquo;s equations are the 11th equations of the book &amp;ldquo;In Pursuit of the Unknown: 17 Equations That Changed the World&amp;rdquo;.
Let&amp;rsquo;s brush over the fact that I have completely forgotten how to handle the mathematics needed to manipulated them from Uni, and talk about some cool things.
I like how Maxwell derived his equations from the many experiments and machines built by Faraday. It&amp;rsquo;s like he polished Faraday&amp;rsquo;s work, or better removed the inessential part and uncovered the shiny mathematical laws that made it possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navier-Stokes Equation</title>
      <link>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-23-17-equations-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 19:22:27 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mokagio.github.io/not-a-journal/post/2016-08-23-17-equations-10/</guid>
      <description>The Navier-Stokes equation is the 10th equation of the book &amp;ldquo;In Pursuit of the Unknown: 17 Equations That Changed the World&amp;rdquo;.
This equation relates the acceleration of a small region of fluid with the forces that act on it.
The fact that this equation is at the base of the mathematical models used to design airplanes already makes it interesting, but what I found fascinating are its application to the study of how blood flows in our veins and arteries, and &amp;ldquo;climate change&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>